# Vijay Rajagopal

vrajago2@vols.utk.edu | 901-721-3528 | US Citizen | vjraj.dev

#### **SUMMARY**

I am currently a Graduate Research Assistant at the University of Tennessee, with four years of research experience. During this time, I developed expertise in detecting and tracking objects in real time using neural networks. Additionally, I have optimized and deployed neural networks to edge devices. During my time researching, I improved my skills related to deep learning, team communication, and product presentation. Currently, I am looking for opportunities in computer vision with high-impact and challenging applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

# The University of Tennessee | Knoxville, TN

Masters Studies in Computer Science (5 Year BS/MS Program)

Overall GPA: 3.85/4.00

Aug 2021 - Present

# The University of Tennessee | Knoxville, TN

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (Honors) w/ Cybersecurity Minor

**Aug 2017 – May 2021** Overall GPA: 3.68/4.00

Courses: Realtime Artificial Intelligence, Introduction to Quantum Computing, Reinforcement Learning

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Graduate Research Assistant for Computer Vision and Image Processing**

Aug 2021 - Present

The University of Tennessee | Dr. Mongi A. Abidi

Knoxville, TN

- Creating and modifying neural networks tasked for Object Detection and Multi-object Tracking
- Working with multi-modal data (optical imaging and RADAR data)
- Optimizing neural networks to run in real-time on low-power devices (Jetson devices, FPGAs)
- Collaborating with diverse range of laboratories to create a commercially-viable product
- Creating methods to increase neural network robustness against data in unideal environments

# Undergraduate Research Assistant for Deep Learning and Image Processing

Jun 2018 – Aug 2021

The University of Tennessee | Dr. Mongi A. Abidi

Knoxville, TN

- Conducting performance analysis on FPGA-capable neural networks
- Testing and modifying facial detection neural networks for large crowds
- Developed program that analyzes network performance against degraded and corrected images

### **International Paper IT Intern**

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

International Paper | Scott Walsh

Memphis, TN

- Assisted setup of Azure instances by researching and documenting network security and traffic policies
- Redesigned SharePoint website for IP's Cloud Readiness Program with HTML, ASPX, and Javascript
- Presented concept dashboard created with Express is, Angular, and MongoDB for IP's Virtual Innovation Forum

# Co-Founder & Lead Developer of Citiwrks

Mar 2019 - Aug 2020

City of Knoxville | Citiwrks LLC

Knoxville, TN

- Created mobile app for City of Knoxville to manage their road repairs (Team size: 4)
- Coordinated with and was funded by City of Knoxville to enhance app features
- App allows city to manage active work tickets, map best routes, and generate statistics
- Developed at hackathon & won three prizes (Best Mobile App, Best Google Cloud Usage, Fan Favorite)

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- **Programming:** Python (PyTorch, Tensorflow), Javascript, C++, C, Objective-C, Typescript, PHP, SQL
- Other Tools: Raspberry Pi, Azure, AWS, Blender 3D, Kali Linux